<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on Not today...</title>
    <link>http://ixday.github.io/tags/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on Not today...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ixday.github.io/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular $parse</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/angular-parse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/angular-parse/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, I have started to be tired of weak example of angular power, so I will go deeper on angular services and directives and wrote some articles about it.
The service $parse is the one who runs on the html to bind data with your javascript. It provides a lot of useful features which can be really interesting especially with directive manipulation.
So, we will illustrate with some examples:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outside Angular</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/outside-angular/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/outside-angular/</guid>
      <description>There are some cases when angular is accessible but we just want to access a specific service without bootstraping an entire application.
For example, in some tests I can load some fixtures with the $http service, or use $compile for a simple template.
It is pretty simple to do that, but it is not clearly explained in the angular documentation. So here is an example:
// The module ng must be loaded angular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 Boilerplate</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/html5-boilerplate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/html5-boilerplate/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we only need to have a boilerplate quickly to test it through a browser. We only want to have the basis, and having it working fine.
You can find here a good generator for what you want. But sometimes, having a snippet in the bash prompt can be needed.
So here is an example:
# stop script if something bad happen set -e # unzip need to have a tempfile to extract properly TMPFILE=&amp;#34;/tmp/tempfile.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>