<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project on Not today...</title>
    <link>http://ixday.github.io/categories/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project on Not today...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 11:46:41 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ixday.github.io/categories/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>vuecc</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/vuecc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 11:46:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/vuecc/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered Vue.js and I really liked it. You just have to add a script tag and you can start coding using this framework.
After a few hours of development, I decided to use SFC (Single File Components) to separate business code from components. And I got a really bad surpise! In order to compile those templates I needed to use a build system (Webpack or Browserify). The tutorial is really good, but&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listing directory with wsgi</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/listing_directory_with_wsgi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/listing_directory_with_wsgi/</guid>
      <description>Recently I ran into an issue with my blog and pelican (the blogging engine I use). For some reasons (which I explain [here]()) I had to develop a small wsgi app which act like the python SimpleHTTPServer.
I tried a lot of things but they never worked as I wanted them to. So, I decided to do this by myself.
Specifications Here are the features I wanted:
 Define a directory as the root (/) directory from which all the files will be served.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small docker project</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/small_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/small_tool/</guid>
      <description>I really like docker (even if I will look at systemd-nspawn), and also gulp. So I decided to create a small tool for serving a directory with a livereload.
The repo is available here
What I have learned  Docker, especially with boot2docker (I am on MacOSX shame on me), is not really flexible:
 no evaluation for environment variables you can not store a variable through multiple run, you will need to do a oneliner e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>