<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Os on Not today...</title>
    <link>http://ixday.github.io/categories/os/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Os on Not today...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:41:14 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ixday.github.io/categories/os/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Start libvirt VM as unprivileged user</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/unprivileged_libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 11:41:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/unprivileged_libvirt/</guid>
      <description>Quick post for starting a VM inside libvirt as a non-root user. Also contains some useful snippets.
I want to start an alpine virt iso (from here) inside kvm through libvirt. But I am sick to run all my virsh commands prefixed with sudo.
DISCLAIMER: This will contain some of my conclusions with my partial understanding of those tools. I am quite sure that all of this can be improved, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to invest on this for the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Mint 2</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/linux_mint_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 15:23:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/linux_mint_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently messed up my laptop (do not play with &lt;code&gt;/etc/apt/preferences&lt;/code&gt; too much!),
and I had to reinstall my distro. I checked my &lt;a href=&#34;http://ixday.github.io/post/linux_mint/&#34;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;
and noticed some missing informations. So here is a second article of things
I needed to fixup when installing LMDE on my Macbook.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Shortcuts</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/bash_shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 09:13:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/bash_shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Here is just a small reminder of common bash shortcuts for everyday use:
Ctrl + A Go to the beginning of the line you are currently typing on Ctrl + E Go to the end of the line you are currently typing on Ctrl + L Clears the Screen, similar to the clear command Ctrl + U Clears the line before the cursor position. If you are at the end of the line, clears the entire line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Mint</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/linux_mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/linux_mint/</guid>
      <description>After a long journey, I finally found the distribution which fits all my need: Linux Mint Debian Edition
Why ?  It is based on debian a distribution which I really like (and not Ubuntu). The default tilling (similar to W7) is really comfortable. Lot of configuration can be done for shortcuts. Support for systemd (Yay \o/). Beautiful UI out of the box (which I didn&amp;rsquo;t have with TWM). And a lot more  Installation As I am on Macbook (once upon a time, I was young and dumb), I need a particular configuration of the partitions for the installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to find LVM volume... with LVM on top of Luks</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/unable_to_find_lvm_volume_with_lvm_on_top_of_luks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/unable_to_find_lvm_volume_with_lvm_on_top_of_luks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following &lt;a href=&#34;{filename}/2015-08-18.debian-install-2.md&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;
I have LVM on top of Luks for my system.
When I boot I encounter the following message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34; data-lang=&#34;text&#34;&gt;  Volume group &amp;#34;vg_ssd&amp;#34; not found
  Skipping volume group vg_ssd
Unable to find LVM volume vg_ssd/lv_root&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears that LVM is started before I open the crypted partition and display this error.
To fix this we will manipulate the initramfs \o/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is in the file &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/initramfs-tools/scripts/local-top/cryptroot&lt;/code&gt;

which starts like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Install 3</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/debian_install_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/debian_install_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I want to install debian on my personal server.
And I want to crypt the FS using Luks, and add LVM on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want it to look like that (like this scheme, a lot of reference
come from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Dm-crypt/Encrypting_an_entire_system&#34;&gt;arch wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian install 2</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/debian_install_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/debian_install_2/</guid>
      <description>After many days of configuration, I finally complete the installation of my perfect &amp;ldquo;workstation&amp;rdquo; ;).
source.list I have to directory for this, first the preferences, then the sources.list.
Just run an aptitude update, and you will some missing gpg keys, now run
apt-key adv --recv-keys --keyserver keyserver.ubuntu.com &amp;lt;key_number&amp;gt; To have your keys installed.
sudo A sudo file is important in order to correctly manage a computer, a simple aptitude install sudo will give you the tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Install</title>
      <link>http://ixday.github.io/post/debian-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ixday.github.io/post/debian-install/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s a fact: I can not install a new system without getting into troubles!
So, here is a small tutorial in which I will aggregate the main issues I encountered and how I solved them.
Creating a bootable USB key on a Mac # plug your USB key, then find it with diskutil list # unmount the usb key (it is mandatory), where X in diskX is the number assigned # to your USB you retrieved with the previous command diskutil unmountDisk /dev/diskX # if you are making a bootable usb key for a Mac run this command, # debian.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>